Guide to the Barbaralee Diamonstein-Spielvogel Collection, 1876-2020 and undated, bulk 1950-2020 RL.10006
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Art and Design Project Files, 1935-2011
  - Inside the Art World, 1967-1994; 5
    - General Working Files, 1967-1994; 7
      - Artist response letters, 1991-1993 (Box 413)
      - Castelli celebration and correspondence, 1994 (Box 413)
      - Mary Christian correspondence, 1993 (Box 413)
      - Completed interviews, 1993 (Box 414)
      - Correspondence, notes, and clippings, 1993-1994, 3 folders (Box 414)
      - Correspondence from Rizzoli and artists, 1992-1993 (Box 414)
      - Correspondence to artists from Barbaralee Diamonstein-Spielvogel, 1992-1993, 2 folders (Box 414)
      - Correspondence to Rizzoli from Jasmine Benyamin, 1992-1993 (Box 414)
      - Exhibition, 1994 (Box 414)
      - First pass, Ann Hamilton, 1993 (Box 414)
      - Forum materials, 1993-1994 (Box 415)
      - Galleys/editing materials, 1993, 2 folders (Box 415)
      - General, 1967-1993 (Box 415)
      - Inside the Art World II, 1996 (Box 415)
      - David Levy, Corcoran Gallery event, 1993-1994 (Box 415)
      - Los Angeles event, 1994 (Box 415)
      - Press clippings, 1994 (Box 415)
      - Promotions, 1993-1994 (Box 415)
      - Questions, drafts, examples, 1991-1993 (Box 415)
      - Release forms, 1992-1993 (Box 416)
      - Rizzoli correspondence, 1992 (Box 416)
      - Rizzoli correspondence, 1994 (Box 416)
      - Status reports, master, 1994 (Box 416)
    - Photographs, 1994; 8
      - J. Carter Brown, Leo Castelli, and Dale Chihuly, circa 1994 (Box 416)
      - Christo, Francesco Clemente, and Chuck Close, circa 1994 (Box 416)
      - Kinshasha Conwill, Douglas Cramer, and Larry Gagosian, circa 1994 (Box 416)
      - Ann Glimcher, Agnes Gund, and Kathy Halbreich, circa 1994 (Box 416)
      - Ann Hamilton, Jenny Holzer, and Jasper Johns, circa 1994 (Box 416)
      - Ellsworth Kelly, Jeff Koons, and Richard Koshalek, circa 1994 (Box 416)
      - Thomas Krens, Barbara Kruger, Roy Lichtenstein, circa 1994 (Box 417)
      - Brice Marden, Philippe de Montebello, and Nam June Paik, circa 1994 (Box 417)
      - Earl Powell, Robert Rauschenberg, and David Ross, circa 1994 (Box 417)
      - Robert Ryman, David Salle, Richard Serra, Joel Shapiro, and Holly Solomon, circa 1994 (Box 417)
      - Kirk Varnedoe, Joel Wachs, William Wegman, and Lawrence Weiner, circa 1994 (Box 417)
      - A-C, circa 1994 (Box 417)
      - C, circa 1994 (Box 417)
      - D-H, circa 1994 (Box 417)
      - I-K, circa 1994 (Box 418)
      - L-R, circa 1994 (Box 418)
      - S, circa 1994 (Box 418)
      - T-Z, circa 1994 (Box 418)
      - Extra photographs and materials, circa 1994 (Box 418)
      - Mixed photographs and negatives, circa 1994 (Box 418)
    - Research Files, 1970-1993; 9
      - J. Carter Brown interview materials, 1992-1993 and undated, 2 folders (Box 419)
      - Leo Castelli interview materials, 1992 and undated (Box 419)
      - Dale Chihuly interview materials, 1992-1993 and undated, folders 1-2 of 4 (Box 419)
      - Dale Chihuly interview materials, 1992-1993 and undated, folders 3-4 of 4 (Box 420)
      - Christo interview materials, 1992 and undated, 2 folders (Box 420)
      - Francesco Clemente interview materials, 1985-1993 and undated (Box 420)
      - Chuck Close interview materials, 1989-1993, folder 1 of 2 (Box 420)
      - Chuck Close interview materials, 1989-1993, folder 2 of 2 (Box 421)
      - Kinshasha Conwill interview materials, 1991-1993 and undated, 2 folders (Box 421)
      - Agnes Gund interview, 1993 (Box 421)
      - Jeff Koons, 1986-1992 (Box 421)
      - Jeff Koons, 1992-1993 (Box 421)
      - Douglas Kramer, 1987-1993, folder 1 of 2 (Box 421)
      - Douglas Kramer, 1987-1993, folder 2 of 2 (Box 422)
      - Barbara Kruger, 1976-1992 (Box 422)
      - Barbara Kruger, 1992-1993 (Box 422)
      - Alexander Liberman, 1971-1981 (Box 422)
      - Roy Lichtenstein, 1978-1981 (Box 422)
      - Roy Lichtenstein, 1981-1992 (Box 422)
      - Roy Lichtenstein, 1992 (Box 422)
      - Roy Lichtenstein, 1992-1993 (Box 423)
      - Brice Marden, 1987-1993 (Box 423)
      - Brice Marden, 1992-1993 (Box 423)
      - Philippe de Montebello, 1981-1993, 2 folders (Box 423)
      - Nam June Paik, 1975-1993 (Box 423)
      - Earl A. Powell III, 1981-1993 (Box 424)
      - Robert Rauschenberg, 1977-1993, 2 folders (Box 424)
      - David Ross, 1991-1993, 3 folders (Box 424)
      - Robert Ryman, 1986-1993 (Box 425)
      - David Salle, 1984-1994, 2 folders (Box 425)
      - Richard Serra, 1970-1993 (Box 425)
      - Joel Shapiro, 1989-1993 (Box 425)
      - Holly Solomon, 1992-1993 (Box 425)
      - Kirk Varnedoe, 1986-1993 (Box 426)
      - Joel Wachs, 1984-1993, 2 folders (Box 426)
      - Joel Wachs, 1984-1993, 2 folders (Box 426)
      - William Wegman, 1981-1993, 2 folders (Box 426)
      - Lawrence Weiner, 1989-1993 (Box 426)
  - Inside New York's Art World, 1965-1993; 6
    Materials deriving from Diamonstein-Spielvogel's book and television series, Inside New York's Art World (1979) are found in this subseries, and include correspondence, interviews, notes, drafts, photographs, clippings, and other papers. Materials are divided into three subseries: General Working Files, Research Files, and Transcripts, arranged alphabetically by folder title. Original folder titles are retained.
    There are corresponding recordings in the Barbaralee Diamonstein-Spielvogel Audiovisual Materials Collection.
    - General Working Files, 1974-1993; 10
      - American photographer (column): Thomas Hess clipping and correspondence, 1980 (Box 427)
      - Book concept from interviews at New School, 1977 (Box 427)
      - Book introduction, back flap, headings - copy and drafts, 1979 (Box 427)
      - Castelli gallery installation, 1981 (Box 427)
      - Castelli-Sonnabend tapes and films, 1978 (Box 427)
      - Castelli-Sonnabend productions costs video, 1978-1980 (Box 427)
      - Charted, 1979 (Box 427)
      - Classroom notes and materials, 1977 (Box 427)
      - Columbia University Oral History Pamphlet, 1976 (Box 427)
      - Columbia University Oral History, 1975-1978 (Box 427)
      - Brian Connell/editing, 1977 (Box 427)
      - Copyright registration, 1980 (Box 427)
      - Exhibition, 22 April-29 April, 1977-1978 (Box 427)
      - First session, undated (Box 427)
      - Galleys, 1976-1980, folders 1-4 of 6 (Box 427)
      - Galleys, 1976-1980, folders 5-6 of 6 (Box 428)
      - Galleys/editing materials, 1993 (Box 428)
      - Galleys/editing materials, 1993, galleys (Box 180)
      - George Lang party, 1979-1980 (Box 428)
      - Hunter College Center for Lifelong Learning, 1974-1979 (Box 428)
      - Hunter College, City University of New York (CUNY), 1974-1976, 2 folders (Box 428)
      - Interview screen shots, 1976-1979 (Box 428)
      - Interview screen shots, 1980, folder 1 of 2 (Box 428)
      - Interview screen shots, 1980, folder 2 of 2 (Box 429)
      - List of interviewees, 1976-1977 (Box 429)
      - List of recorded interviews, 1977-1978 (Box 429)
      - Manhattan Cable Television, 1979 (Box 429)
      - Miscellaneous publicity, 1979-1980 (Box 429)
      - The New School: announcements, 1979 (Box 429)
      - The New School: class materials, 1978 (Box 429)
      - The New School: video release, 1976-1980 (Box 429)
      - New York Times: Castelli ad/videotape show, 1977-1980 (Box 429)
      - New York Times: Herb Mitgang, undated (Box 429)
      - Press releases, 1980 (Box 429)
      - Production notes, 1977-1978 (Box 429)
      - Public relations, 1978-1979 (Box 429)
      - Publisher's Weekly, 1979 (Box 429)
      - Receipts, 1979 (Box 429)
      - Releases, 1977-1978, 2 folders (Box 429)
      - Rizzoli contract/lists, 1979-1980 (Box 429)
      - Rizzoli fall catalog/papers, 1980 (Box 429)
      - Scrapbook, 1979-1980 (Box 429)
      - United Press International by Frederick Winship, 1979 (Box 429)
      - WNYC- Inside New York's Art World, 1977-1978 (Box 429)
      - Women's Wear Daily by Howard Kissel, 1980 (Box 429)
    - Research Files, 1965-1982; 11
      - Tom Armstrong/Whitney Museum, 1977-1979 (Box 430)
      - Elizabeth Barlow and Gordon Davis, 1978-1979 (Box 430)
      - Doug Davis, 1975-1981 (Box 430)
      - Henry Geldzahler, 1965-1979 (Box 430)
      - Brenden Gill, 1976-1977 and undated (Box 430)
      - Milton Glaser and Ivan Chermayeff, 1971-1977 (Box 430)
      - Grace Glueck, 1973-1982 (Box 430)
      - Alana Heiss, 1979 and undated (Box 430)
      - Tom Hess, 1967-1977 (Box 430)
      - Jamake Hightower, 1979-1981 (Box 430)
      - Ada Louise Huxtable, 1977-1978 (Box 430)
      - Robert Indiana, 1974 and undated (Box 430)
      - Alex Katz, 1971-1977 and undated (Box 430)
      - Kate Lloyd, Leonard Lauder, Bernadine Morris, undated (Box 430)
      - Alice Neel, 1970-1978 (Box 430)
      - Beverly Pepper and Sarah Cushing Faunce, 1977-1979 (Box 430)
    - Transcripts, 1976-1981; 12
      - Richard Anuszkiewicz and Jacques Kaplan: signed release/transcript, 1977 (Box 431)
      - Thomas Armstrong: signed release/transcript, 1976 (Box 431)
      - Edward Larrabee Barnes: book transcript, 1979 (Box 431)
      - Edward Larrabee Barnes: signed release/transcript, 1979 (Box 431)
      - Edward Larrabee Barnes: transcript, 1976-1980 (Box 431)
      - Romare Bearden: book transcript, 1979 (Box 431)
      - Romare Bearden: signed release/transcript, 1979 (Box 431)
      - Romare Bearden: transcript, 1976-1980 (Box 431)
      - Isabel Bishop: book transcript, 1979 (Box 431)
      - Isabel Bishop: signed release/transcript, 1979 (Box 431)
      - Isabel Bishop: transcript, 1976-1980 (Box 431)
      - Carter Brown: book transcript, 1979 (Box 432)
      - Carter Brown: signed release/transcript, 1978 (Box 432)
      - Carter Brown: transcript, 1976-1980 (Box 432)
      - Cornell Capa: signed release/transcript, 1979 (Box 432)
      - Cornell Capa: transcript, not used 1979 (Box 432)
      - Leo Castelli: signed transcript, 1977 (Box 432)
      - Leo Castelli and Joseph Kosuth: signed release/transcript, 1977 (Box 432)
      - Christo and Jean Claude Christo: book transcript, 1977 (Box 432)
      - Christo and Jean Claude Christo: memoir, 1979 (Box 432)
      - Christo and Jean Claude Christo: signed release/transcript, 1979 (Box 432)
      - Christo and Jean Claude Christo: transcript, 1976-1980 (Box 432)
      - Chuck Close: book transcript, 1977 (Box 432)
      - Chuck Close: transcript, 1976-1980 (Box 432)
      - Jim Dine: book transcript, 1977 (Box 433)
      - Jim Dine: signed release/transcript, 1977 (Box 433)
      - Jim Dine transcript, 1976-1980 (Box 433)
      - Henry Geldzahler: signed release/transcript, 1979 (Box 433)
      - Henry Geldzahler: transcript not used, 1977 (Box 433)
      - Brendan Gill: book transcript, 1978 (Box 433)
      - Brendan Gill: signed release/transcript, 1978 (Box 433)
      - Brendan Gill: transcript, 1976-1980 (Box 433)
      - Milton Glaser: book transcript, 1976 (Box 433)
      - Milton Glaser: signed release/transcript, 1976-1978 (Box 433)
      - Milton Glaser: transcript, 1976-1980 (Box 433)
      - Grace Glueck and Lucas Samaras: signed release/transcript, 1977 (Box 433)
      - Nancy Graves and Andre Emmerich: signed release/transcript, 1977 (Box 433)
      - Richard Haas: signed release/transcript, 1978 (Box 434)
      - Thomas Hess: book transcript, 1977 (Box 434)
      - Thomas Hess: signed release/transcript, 1977 (Box 434)
      - Thomas Hess: transcript, 1977 (Box 434)
      - Sheila Hicks: final transcript, 1981 (Box 434)
      - Thomas Hoving: signed release/transcripts, 1976 (Box 434)
      - Robert Indiana: book transcript, 1977 (Box 434)
      - Robert Indiana: signed release/transcript, 1977 (Box 434)
      - Robert Indiana: transcript, 1976-1980 (Box 434)
      - Robert Indiana: video transcript, 1978 (Box 604)
      - Philip Johnson: book transcript, 1978 (Box 434)
      - Philip Johnson: signed release/transcript, 1978 (Box 434)
      - Philip Johnson: transcript, 1976-1980 (Box 434)
      - Ivan Karp: book transcript, 1978 (Box 435)
      - Ivan Karp: signed release/transcript, 1978 (Box 435)
      - Ivan Karp: transcript, 1976-1980 (Box 435)
      - Lee Krasner: book transcript, 1978 (Box 435)
      - Lee Krasner: signed release/transcript, 1978 (Box 435)
      - Lee Krasner: transcript, 1976-1980 (Box 435)
      - Alex Katz: signed release/transcript, 1978 (Box 435)
      - Alexander Liberman and Robert Hughes: signed release/transcript, 1977 (Box 435)
      - Alexander Liberman: signed release/transcript, 1978 (Box 435)
      - Roy Lichtenstein and Leo Castelli: book transcript, 1976 (Box 435)
      - Roy Lichtenstein and Leo Castelli: signed release/transcript, 1976 (Box 435)
      - Thomas Messer: book transcript, 1976 (Box 436)
      - Thomas Messer: memoir, 1976-1978 (Box 436)
      - Thomas Messer: signed release/transcript, 1976 (Box 436)
      - Thomas Messer: transcript, 1976-1980 (Box 436)
      - Robert Motherwell: book transcript, 1979 (Box 436)
      - Robert Motherwell: memoir, 1977-1979 (Box 436)
      - Robert Motherwell: signed release/transcript, 1977-1979, 2 folders (Box 436)
      - Alice Neel: book transcript, 1976-1980 (Box 436)
      - Alice Neel: signed release/transcript, 1979 (Box 436)
      - Alice Neel: transcript, 1978 (Box 436)
      - Louise Nevelson and Arnold Glimcher: signed release/transcript, 1976-1980 (Box 436)
      - Louise Nevelson: book transcript, 1977 (Box 437)
      - Louise Nevelson: signed release/transcript, 1977 (Box 437)
      - Louise Nevelson: transcript, 1976-1980 (Box 437)
      - Richard Oldenburg: signed release/transcript, 1976 (Box 437)
      - Partisan Review: transcript, 1979 (Box 437)
      - I.M. Pei: book transcript, 1978 (Box 437)
      - I.M. Pei: signed release/transcript, 1978 (Box 437)
      - I.M. Pei: transcript, 1978 (Box 437)
      - Beverly Pepper and Sarah Cushing Faunce: book transcript, 1978 (Box 437)
      - Beverly Pepper and Sarah Cushing Faunce: memoir, 1978 (Box 437)
      - Beverly Pepper and Sarah Cushing Faunce: transcript, 1976-1980, 2 folders (Box 437)
      - Robert Rauschenberg and Leo Castelli: book transcript, 1977-1978 (Box 438)
      - Robert Rauschenberg and Leo Castelli: signed release/transcript, 1977 (Box 438)
      - Robert Rauschenberg and Leo Castelli: transcript, 1976-1980 (Box 438)
      - Larry Rivers: book transcript, 1977 (Box 438)
      - Larry Rivers: transcript, 1977 (Box 438)
      - Robert Ryman: book transcript, 1977 (Box 438)
      - Robert Ryman: signed release/transcript, 1977 (Box 438)
      - Robert Ryman: transcript, 1976-1980 (Box 438)
      - Lucas Samaras: book transcript, 1979 (Box 438)
      - Lucas Samaras: signed release/transcript, 1979 (Box 438)
      - Lucas Samaras: transcript, 1976-1980 (Box 438)
      - George Segal: book transcript, 1978 (Box 438)
      - George Segal: memoir, 1976-1980 (Box 438)
      - George Segal: signed release/transcript, 1978 (Box 439)
      - Raphael Soyer: book transcript, 1979 (Box 439)
      - Raphael Soyer: signed release/transcript, 1979 (Box 439)
      - Raphael Soyer: transcript, 1976-1980 (Box 439)
      - Lisa Taylor: signed release/transcript, 1976, 2 folders (Box 439)
  - Interior Design: The New Freedom, 1972-1984; 7
    This subseries is composed of files of correspondence, interviews, notes, drafts, photographs, clippings, and administrative materials pertaining to Diamonstein-Spielvogel's book and television series, Interior Design: The New Freedom (1980-1983).
    As with other subseries, materials are arranged into three subgroups: General Working Files, Research Files, and Transcripts, arranged alphabetically by folder title. Original folder titles have been retained.
    Corresponding recordings are located in the Barbaralee Diamonstein-Spielvogel Audiovisual Materials Collection.
    - General Working Files, 1980-1984; 13
      - American Broadcasting Company (ABC) proposals, correspondence, meetings with David Gordon, 1980-1981 (Box 439)
      - American Institute of Architects Journal, 1983 (Box 439)
      - Audio tapes, undated (Box 439)
      - Avenue, 1982 (Box 439)
      - Biographies, 1981 (Box 439)
      - Blank permissions forms, 1981 (Box 439)
      - Bloomingdale's series, 1982 (Box 439)
      - Book flow charts - text and photography, 1981 (Box 439)
      - Book order letters, 1982 (Box 439)
      - Castelli exhibition invitation, 1982 (Box 439)
      - Castelli show, 1982 (Box 439)
      - Catalogue copy, 1981 (Box 439)
      - Christian Science Monitor, 1982 (Box 439)
      - Class names and numbers, 1981 (Box 439)
      - Clothes, 1980 (Box 439)
      - Cooper-Hewitt: invitation, 1982 (Box 439)
      - Cooper-Hewitt: press release, 1982 (Box 439)
      - Cooper-Hewitt: show, 1982 (Box 440)
      - Cooper-Hewitt: thank you letters, 1982 (Box 440)
      - Correspondence, memos to participants, 1981-1982 (Box 440)
      - Correspondence with press, 1982 (Box 440)
      - Correspondence with publisher, 1982 (Box 440)
      - Exhibition proposals, 1981 (Box 440)
      - Flow chart/addresses, 1981 (Box 440)
      - Poster, 1981 (Box 440)
      - Posters for Interior Design, oversize, circa 1981, 4 items (Box 179)
      - Galleys, 1981 (Box 440)
      - Galleys, larger size, 1981 (Box 641)
      - General questions, 1981-1982 (Box 440)
      - Goldberger introduction, 1981 (Box 440)
      - Historic preservation, 1982 (Box 440)
      - House Beautiful excerpts, 1981 (Box 440)
      - House and Garden excerpts, 1981 (Box 440)
      - Introduction, Barbaralee Diamonstein, 1981, 2 folders (Box 440)
      - Legal contracts, correspondence, etc., 1980-1981 (Box 440)
      - Letters to publishers and correspondence back, 1982 (Box 440)
      - Library Journal, 1983 (Box 440)
      - Materials release forms, 1981-1983 (Box 440)
      - New School/Parson correspondence, 1980 (Box 440)
      - New York Times, 1981-1982 (Box 441)
      - New York Times: Castelli, 1982 (Box 441)
      - New York Times: Cooper-Hewitt, 1982 (Box 441)
      - New York Times: Review, 1980 (Box 441)
      - Notes, correspondence, contracts, 1980-1984 (Box 441)
      - Notes on room/space, 1981 (Box 441)
      - October 27 symposium, 1982 (Box 441)
      - Opening/closing remarks, 1981 (Box 441)
      - Photographs, circa 1981 (Box 441)
        Informal color snapshots taken on the set of the show "Interior Design: The New Freedom," as well as larger black-and-white publicity photographs of Diamonstein-Spielvogel and her interviewees.
      - Photographs received/photograph flow charts, 1981-1983 (Box 441)
      - Poster, oversize, 1981 (Box 598)
      - Poster copy and drafts/correspondence to Cipe Pineles, 1980 (Box 441)
      - Poster/Cipe Pineles - oversize materials, 1980 (Box 179)
      - Press correspondence and memos, 1980-1982 (Box 441)
      - Press coverage, 1981 (Box 441)
      - Press kit, 1980-1982 (Box 441)
      - Press releases, 1982 (Box 441)
      - Production, 1981 (Box 441)
      - Publisher's Weekly, 1982 (Box 441)
      - Reprints, Interiors magazine correspondence, 1981 (Box 441)
      - Research, 1980-1981 (Box 441)
      - Research, 1980-1981 - oversize poster (Box 642)
      - Rizzoli: cover designs, 1981 (Box 441)
      - Rizzoli, 1981, oversize book cover layout (Box 641)
      - Rizzoli: fall book list, 1982 (Box 441)
      - Rizzoli: press release, 1982 (Box 441)
      - Rizzoli: publicity, 1982 (Box 441)
      - Schedules, 1981 (Box 441)
      - Scrapbook, 1981-1982 (Box 441)
      - Screen shots of interviews, circa 1981 (Box 441)
      - Seminar at Castelli, 1982 (Box 441)
      - Signed permission copies, 1981 (Box 441)
      - Signed permission forms, 1981 (Box 442)
      - Tape edits, 1981 (Box 442)
      - Transcript flow chart, 1981 (Box 442)
      - Visuals to be returned to Esto Photographics, 1981-1983 (Box 442)
      - Volunteer ushers, 1981 (Box 442)
      - Working Woman excerpt, Sarah Tomerlin Lee, 1982 (Box 442)
    - Research Files, 1972-1982; 14
      - Ward Bennett, 1980 (Box 442)
      - Bob Bray/Mike Schaible, 1979-1981 (Box 442)
      - Mario Buatta, 1972-1983 (Box 442)
      - Angelo Donghia, 1980-1981 (Box 442)
      - Joseph Paul D'Urso, 1980-1981 (Box 442)
      - Mark Hampton, 1980-1981 (Box 442)
      - Sarah Tomerlin Lee, 1980-1982 (Box 442)
      - Warren Platner, 1981 (Box 442)
      - John Saladino, 1979-1981 (Box 443)
      - Robert A.M. Stern, 1974-1981, 2 folders (Box 443)
      - Massimo and Lella Vignelli, 1979-1980, 2 folders (Box 443)
      - Vignelli, 1979-1980, oversize item - article (Box 642)
    - Transcripts, 1981; 15
      - Ward Bennett transcripts, 1981 (Box 443)
      - Bob Bray/Mike Schaible transcripts, 1981 (Box 443)
      - Mario Buatta transcripts, 1981, folder 1 of 3 (Box 443)
      - Mario Buatta transcripts, 1981, folders 2-3 of 3 (Box 444)
      - Angelo Donghia transcripts, 1981 (Box 444)
      - Joseph D'Urso transcripts, 1981 (Box 444)
      - Final transcripts, 1981, 4 folders (Box 444)
      - Mark Hampton transcripts, 1981 (Box 445)
      - Sarah Tomerlin Lee transcripts, 1981, 2 folders (Box 445)
      - Warren Platner transcripts, 1981 (Box 445)
      - John Saladino transcripts, 1981 (Box 445)
      - Robert A.M. Stern transcripts, 1981 (Box 445)
      - Massimo and Lella Vignelli transcripts, 1981 (Box 445)
  - Art and Design Subject Files, 1950-2011; 8
    This subseries houses notes, clippings, proposals, correspondence, printed materials, and other general files relevant to the arts that do not belong to a particular project, or belong to a proposed project. Arranged alphabetically by folder title. Original folder titles have been retained.
    - American Broadcasting Company (ABC) proposals, 1980 (Box 447)
    - American Institute of Architects panel, 1993 (Box 379)
    - Antiques conference, 1976-1980 (Box 447)
    - Jacques d'Amboise, 1984 (Box 447)
    - Architectural League 100th anniversary - articles, 1979 (Box 379)
    - Art-Deco Miami Preservation League, 1978-1979 (Box 447)
    - Art legislation, 1977-1979 (Box 447)
    - Arts and Entertainment network, (A&E) press materials and program schedule, 1984-1985 and undated (Box 447)
    - Arts International, 1981 (Box 448)
    - Arts tax report, 1973-1974 (Box 448)
    - Association of Artist-Run Galleries, 1975-1978 (Box 448)
    - Barnard intern applications, 1980-1981 (Box 448)
    - Jean-Charles Bouloc, 1963-1971 (Box 448)
    - Jean-Charles Bouloc, 1963-1971, oversize print (Box 642)
    - Business and the Arts: Speeches, biographies, and questions, 1974-1980 (Box 391)
    - Business and the Arts: Articles on art and economic partners, 1974-1980, 2 folders (Box 392)
    - Castelli gallery materials, 1978-1986 (Box 448)
      Publicity, notes, correspondence, and glossy photos of gallery installation relating to Diamonstein-Spielvogel's videotaped interviews.
    - CBS News, art and culture consultant, 1980 (Box 448)
    - Chesterwood benefit, 1982 (Box 448)
    - Christo, small mounted color transparency of Christo collage, Project for Little Bay, Australia, 1969, undated (Box 448)
    - Christo, Running Fences, glossy black-and-white photographs, 1972-1976 (Box 448)
    - Clippings regarding Diamonstein-Spielvogel's projects, series, 1976, 1981 (Box 76)
    - Betty Comden and Adolph Green, publicity, correspondence, interview questions, and notes, 1976-1979 (Box 448)
    - Cooper-Hewitt newsletter, 1977 (Box 76)
    - Corporation for Entertainment and Learning correspondence, 1982-1983 (Box 448)
    - Contemporary Arts Center, Ohio, 1978 (Box 448)
    - Merce Cunningham video, emails, 2011 (Box 448)
    - Engraving/graphics, undated (Box 448)
    - Famous artist doodle, puzzle patterns, undated (Box 448)
    - Helen Frankenthaler, 1985-1989 (Box 448)
    - Peter Freeman Incorporated, 2004 (Box 448)